<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>wayland on A collection of random ideas so I don&#39;t have to google again</title>
    <link>https://rushichaudhari.github.io/tags/wayland/</link>
    <description>Recent content in wayland on A collection of random ideas so I don&#39;t have to google again</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 19 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://rushichaudhari.github.io/tags/wayland/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Wayvnc Arch Linux (Pinephone)</title>
      <link>https://rushichaudhari.github.io/posts/2022-05-19-wayvnc-arch-linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rushichaudhari.github.io/posts/2022-05-19-wayvnc-arch-linux/</guid>
      <description>Traditionally we have been using Xorg or X11 as the display server on linux. Wayland is a similar display server which aims to be a modern and more optimized. I&amp;rsquo;m not much used to wayland and this is a guide for using wayvnc, a vnc server for wayland. Any vnc client like tigervnc/ realvncviewer can be used.
# Install wayvncsudo pacman -S wayvnc Create a config with the authentication info and load it using the &amp;ndash;config command line option or place it at the default location $HOME/.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pretty pop up cheatsheet for SWMO</title>
      <link>https://rushichaudhari.github.io/posts/2021-07-02-swmo-generate-cheatsheet-from-config/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rushichaudhari.github.io/posts/2021-07-02-swmo-generate-cheatsheet-from-config/</guid>
      <description>I had recently moved to awesomewm from i3wm, some default keybindings were different and It had a really cool command to access cheatsheet which looked like below
Then I got a linux phone where swaywm was highly popular in development, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t find anything good enough to create that cheatsheet like the one found in awesomewm. This script allows me to parse the swaywm config, and create a cheatsheet. It can later be made more pretty through https://carbon.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
