<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>selenium on A collection of random ideas so I don&#39;t have to google again</title>
    <link>https://rushichaudhari.github.io/categories/selenium/</link>
    <description>Recent content in selenium on A collection of random ideas so I don&#39;t have to google again</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://rushichaudhari.github.io/categories/selenium/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Automate Google forms without selenium</title>
      <link>https://rushichaudhari.github.io/posts/2020-07-02-automate-forms-without-selenium/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rushichaudhari.github.io/posts/2020-07-02-automate-forms-without-selenium/</guid>
      <description>In the previous year, I had posted a script to fill google forms using selenium, and containerizing it with docker to run it parallelly. This is an alternative way to do the same using post requests.
I had created a google form using the default template shown below.
Which had fields like To get started we need to capture the request. I&amp;rsquo;ve used burp suite tool to capture, there are many alternative tools you can google.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automate Google forms without selenium</title>
      <link>https://rushichaudhari.github.io/posts/2020-07-03-lstm-stock-prediction-worth-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rushichaudhari.github.io/posts/2020-07-03-lstm-stock-prediction-worth-it/</guid>
      <description>LSTMS for stock price predictions, worth it ? The internet is now flooded with &amp;ldquo;predicting stock market prices using LSTM&amp;rdquo;. I went through 9 articles which I found on websites like medium, KDnuggets, etc. And I realized almost 6-7 out of them showed good results. But none of them showed their real-life use-case, The question is really helpful?
LSTMS predict T+1th term by previous k terms of time-series say k=2 So we need to have T and T-1 to predict T+2</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Webscraping 1 minute stock data from tradingview</title>
      <link>https://rushichaudhari.github.io/posts/2020-06-28-trading-view-scraping/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rushichaudhari.github.io/posts/2020-06-28-trading-view-scraping/</guid>
      <description>How I webscraped 1 minute stock data from tradingview After a long die-hard trying I managed to get 1 minute stock data for free. My previous tries were using selenium and beautifulsoup modules in python. But the data is highly obfuscated so I was not able to find the exact HTML element to scrape. If you manage to do this using selenium please comment below.
Probably the data is being loaded up as SVG which is why it isn&amp;rsquo;t being seen in html inspect element.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
