<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>A collection of random ideas so I don&#39;t have to google again</title>
    <link>https://rushichaudhari.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on A collection of random ideas so I don&#39;t have to google again</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://rushichaudhari.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Lets Clone the Voice of Priyanka Chopra Jonas</title>
      <link>https://rushichaudhari.github.io/posts/2022-01-12-lets-clone-the-voice-of-priyanka-chopra-jonas/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rushichaudhari.github.io/posts/2022-01-12-lets-clone-the-voice-of-priyanka-chopra-jonas/</guid>
      <description>I had decided to get my email reminders using any celebrity&amp;rsquo;s voice in my previous post Alexa AI for reminding important emails and reminders. Here is a small step towards it :D
If you don&amp;rsquo;t know how Priyanka Chopra sounds like, here is a real sample     Sample synthesized voice 1   Sample synthesized voice 2   Sample synthesized voice 3   Real voice of Amitabh Bachchan     Sample synthesized voice for Amitabh Bachchan This one is more robotic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alexa AI for reminding important emails and reminders</title>
      <link>https://rushichaudhari.github.io/posts/2021-12-19-alexa-remind-emails/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rushichaudhari.github.io/posts/2021-12-19-alexa-remind-emails/</guid>
      <description>Motivation :- It was the third time I missed reading my email and picking up shifts for my oncampus job. I did try creating labels and filtering them but that didn&amp;rsquo;t show any progress in improvement. It&amp;rsquo;s really stressful when I get the notification that something needs a response from me right away. I had to make sure that I was not missing this next time. It is then when I decided I need to build a system to process and remind me this.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pca VS AutoEncoders</title>
      <link>https://rushichaudhari.github.io/posts/2021-11-25-pca-vs-autoencoders/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rushichaudhari.github.io/posts/2021-11-25-pca-vs-autoencoders/</guid>
      <description>PCA import numpy as np import sklearn import matplotlib.pyplot as plt from sklearn.decomposition import PCA from sklearn.preprocessing import StandardScaler from sklearn.preprocessing import MinMaxScaler from tensorflow.keras.datasets import fashion_mnist import seaborn as sns import os import gzip import sys # The number of components for pca N_COMP = 100 #@param {type:&amp;#34;integer&amp;#34;} #Load data: (X_train, y_train), (X_test, y_test) = fashion_mnist.load_data() #Design matrix print(&amp;#39;Design matrix size: {}&amp;#39;.format(X_train.shape)) Downloading data from https://storage.googleapis.com/tensorflow/tf-keras-datasets/train-labels-idx1-ubyte.gz 32768/29515 [=================================] - 0s 0us/step 40960/29515 [=========================================] - 0s 0us/step Downloading data from https://storage.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publishing HUGO Post to DevTo Using GitHub CI and CD Pipeline</title>
      <link>https://rushichaudhari.github.io/posts/2021-11-06-publishing-hugo-post-to-devto-using-github-ci-and-cd-pipeline/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rushichaudhari.github.io/posts/2021-11-06-publishing-hugo-post-to-devto-using-github-ci-and-cd-pipeline/</guid>
      <description>Why this tool?  There are aleady a few github actions available like publish-devto and markdown-to-devto They seem to be failing despite of the valid data in the markdown file. For a large amount of posts there was no option to add a break and the API got overflowed.  Steps to set up Creating API Keys in Dev.To Login to dev.to and then go to accounts and create new api key.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enable Secure Boot on Dualboot</title>
      <link>https://rushichaudhari.github.io/posts/2021-11-01-enable-secure-boot-on-dualboot/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rushichaudhari.github.io/posts/2021-11-01-enable-secure-boot-on-dualboot/</guid>
      <description>Repo to https://wiki.archlinux.org/title/Unified_Extensible_Firmware_Interface/Secure_Boot#Using_a_signed_boot_loader
Tips  preloader-signed works with systemd boot If you have grub and want to move to systemd-boot refer this  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ml Pipelines on Kubeflow on Localhost</title>
      <link>https://rushichaudhari.github.io/posts/2021-11-01-ml-pipelines-on-kubeflow-on-localhost/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rushichaudhari.github.io/posts/2021-11-01-ml-pipelines-on-kubeflow-on-localhost/</guid>
      <description>What is Vagrant ? https://www.janbasktraining.com/blog/vagrant-tutorial/
Install Vagrant
sudo pacman -S vagrant vagrant plugin install vagrant-vbguest vagrant-share Note: There is also vagrant libvirt plugin for qemu
vagrant plugin install vagrant-libvirt but this doesn&amp;rsquo;t work with kubeflow
Install virtualbox
sudo pacman -S virtualbox  for the linux kernel, choose virtualbox-host-modules-arch for any other kernel (including linux-lts), choose virtualbox-host-dkms  Load the vbox drv module
sudo modprobe vboxdrv Make sure to put path for Virtualbox where you have a lot of space (50GB+)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Switch to Systemd From Grub</title>
      <link>https://rushichaudhari.github.io/posts/2021-11-01-switch-to-systemd-from-grub/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rushichaudhari.github.io/posts/2021-11-01-switch-to-systemd-from-grub/</guid>
      <description>I have two efi partitions, p1 for windows and p4 for Arch
sudo fdisk -l
Add the efi entry in /etc/fstab
get the UUID from sudo blkid
Mount the /efi
sudo mount /efi &amp;amp;&amp;amp; ls /efi
The structure would look something like
Install ucode for my amd machine it is
sudo pacman -S amd-ucode
Reinstall linux kernel
sudo pacman -S linux linux-headers
mkinitcpio -P
Add the following in
sudo nano /efi/loader/entries/arch.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bookmark Linux Commands using Keep</title>
      <link>https://rushichaudhari.github.io/posts/2021-10-28-bookmark-linux-commands-keep/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rushichaudhari.github.io/posts/2021-10-28-bookmark-linux-commands-keep/</guid>
      <description>Why keep ?  opensource can export commands from ~/.keep/commands.json  My branch now supports running commands with id https://github.com/rushic24/keep
Add command: keep new</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Webscraping 1 minute stock data from tradingview</title>
      <link>https://rushichaudhari.github.io/posts/2020-06-28-trading-view-scraping/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Dec 2020 01:21:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rushichaudhari.github.io/posts/2020-06-28-trading-view-scraping/</guid>
      <description>How I webscraped 1 minute stock data from tradingview After a long die-hard trying I managed to get 1 minute stock data for free. My previous tries were using selenium and beautifulsoup modules in python. But the data is highly obfuscated so I was not able to find the exact HTML element to scrape. If you manage to do this using selenium please comment below.
Probably the data is being loaded up as SVG which is why it isn&amp;rsquo;t being seen in html inspect element.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Machine Learning resources</title>
      <link>https://rushichaudhari.github.io/posts/2020-12-20-my-machine-learning-resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Dec 2020 19:22:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rushichaudhari.github.io/posts/2020-12-20-my-machine-learning-resources/</guid>
      <description>Machine Learning Concepts. Decision Theory / Risk Estimation Machine Learning #09 Statistical Decision Theory: Regression
OLS Assumptions 7 Classical Assumptions of Ordinary Least Squares (OLS) Linear Regression - Statistics By Jim
The Gauss-Markov Theorem and BLUE OLS Coefficient Estimates The Gauss-Markov Theorem and BLUE OLS Coefficient Estimates - Statistics By Jim
PCA Making sense of principal component analysis, eigenvectors &amp;amp; eigenvalues
PCA (Overview) StatQuest: Principal Component Analysis (PCA), Step-by-Step
PCA Math Principal Component Analysis (The Math) : Data Science Concepts</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adding Netlify CMS to Existing GitHub Pages Site Within 10 Minutes</title>
      <link>https://rushichaudhari.github.io/posts/2020-11-28-adding-netlify-cms-to-existing-github-pages-site-within-10-minutes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Nov 2020 05:27:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rushichaudhari.github.io/posts/2020-11-28-adding-netlify-cms-to-existing-github-pages-site-within-10-minutes/</guid>
      <description>Creating an GitHub OAuth App First, go to GitHub Dev Settings and click New OAuth App. Or just click here: https://github.com/settings/developers
Enter whatever you like for Application name and Homepage URL.
In Authorization callback URL, enter: https://api.netlify.com/auth/done.
Once finished, leave the page in the background. You will need the Client ID and Client Secret on this page later.
Creating a Netlify Site … Relax! We’re just creating one, without actually using it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Change Docker Storage Location</title>
      <link>https://rushichaudhari.github.io/posts/2021-11-11-how-to-change-docker-storage-location/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rushichaudhari.github.io/posts/2021-11-11-how-to-change-docker-storage-location/</guid>
      <description>You can easily change the Docker default storage location by creating the daemon.json file and pointing to another location in that file.
It happened to me several times that I didn’t have enough space in my root partition to store Docker containers and I had to move the Docker default storage location to another partition. In this post, I wrote down how to do that for my readership and future myself :)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://rushichaudhari.github.io/posts/2020-11-25-pca-vs-autoencoders/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rushichaudhari.github.io/posts/2020-11-25-pca-vs-autoencoders/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A prebuilt kali-linux with GUI aka vnc in docker in 2 seconds</title>
      <link>https://rushichaudhari.github.io/posts/2020-05-14-docker-vnc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rushichaudhari.github.io/posts/2020-05-14-docker-vnc/</guid>
      <description>This guide assumes you already know what is docker and docker, vncviewer installed on your system The docker image given at https://hub.docker.com/search?q=&amp;amp;type=image is a blank kali image with 0 tools.
Let us create a light-weight custom image with the tools needed. The following are the tools which I think are commonly used in kali you can add/remove a few from that list.
aircrack-ng crackmapexec crunch curl dirb dirbuster dnsenum dnsrecon dnsutils dos2unix enum4linux exploitdb ftp git gobuster hashcat hping3 hydra impacket-scripts john joomscan masscan metasploit-framework mimikatz nasm ncat netcat-traditional nikto nmap patator php powersploit proxychains python-pip python2 python3 recon-ng responder samba samdump2 smbclient smbmap snmp socat sqlmap sslscan theharvester vim wafw00f weevely wfuzz whois wordlists wpscan Creating Dockerfile</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adding wifi connection without GUI for enterprise wifi like at universities/ offices with PEAP</title>
      <link>https://rushichaudhari.github.io/posts/2021-09-12-nmcli-enterprise-wifi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rushichaudhari.github.io/posts/2021-09-12-nmcli-enterprise-wifi/</guid>
      <description># nmcli con add type wifi ifname wlan0 con-name CONNECTION_NAME ssid SSID # nmcli con edit id CONNECTION_NAME nmcli&amp;gt; set ipv4.method auto nmcli&amp;gt; set 802-1x.eap peap nmcli&amp;gt; set 802-1x.phase2-auth mschapv2 nmcli&amp;gt; set 802-1x.identity USERNAME nmcli&amp;gt; set 802-1x.password PASSWORD nmcli&amp;gt; set wifi-sec.key-mgmt wpa-eap nmcli&amp;gt; save nmcli&amp;gt; activate </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automate Google forms without selenium</title>
      <link>https://rushichaudhari.github.io/posts/2020-07-02-automate-forms-without-selenium/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rushichaudhari.github.io/posts/2020-07-02-automate-forms-without-selenium/</guid>
      <description>In the previous year, I had posted a script to fill google forms using selenium, and containerizing it with docker to run it parallelly. This is an alternative way to do the same using post requests.
I had created a google form using the default template shown below.
Which had fields like To get started we need to capture the request. I&amp;rsquo;ve used burp suite tool to capture, there are many alternative tools you can google.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Compiling fceux on Debian 10 buster</title>
      <link>https://rushichaudhari.github.io/posts/2020-01-29-compiling-fceux-on-debian-buster/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rushichaudhari.github.io/posts/2020-01-29-compiling-fceux-on-debian-buster/</guid>
      <description>I came across this wonderful video https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=qv6UVOQ0F44. It took me into searching for its code to implement that. And here are a few.
https://github.com/Mario-brows/Brows-Super-Mario https://github.com/lopatin96/Lua-SNES-GenNeurNetwork The main problem in them is they use BizHawk Emulator, which I was not successful in compiling for my debian OS, Its stable only for windows machines. Then I found its alternative fceux Which can handle lua scripts too!.
The following steps are what I used to compile it successfully.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Imp links for few scripts or codes</title>
      <link>https://rushichaudhari.github.io/posts/2020-04-08-imp-links/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rushichaudhari.github.io/posts/2020-04-08-imp-links/</guid>
      <description>Create openvpn tested on debian/ubuntu on cloud https://github.com/Nyr/openvpn-install</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LSTMS for stock price predictions, worth it ?</title>
      <link>https://rushichaudhari.github.io/posts/2020-07-03-lstm-stock-prediction-worth-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rushichaudhari.github.io/posts/2020-07-03-lstm-stock-prediction-worth-it/</guid>
      <description>The internet is now flooded with &amp;ldquo;predicting stock market prices using LSTM&amp;rdquo;. I went through 9 articles which I found on websites like medium, KDnuggets, etc. And I realized almost 6-7 out of them showed good results. But none of them showed their real-life use-case, The question is really helpful?
LSTMS predict T+1th term by previous k terms of time-series say k=2 So we need to have T and T-1 to predict T+2</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Thunderbird config</title>
      <link>https://rushichaudhari.github.io/posts/2021-10-29-mythunderbird-config/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rushichaudhari.github.io/posts/2021-10-29-mythunderbird-config/</guid>
      <description>Why thunderbird?  Opensource Can write and export email filters  Extensions:  Disable sort  To quickly find all your filter setting files on Linux, run
find ~/.thunderbird/ -name msgFilterRules.dat </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Not authorized to perform this operation</title>
      <link>https://rushichaudhari.github.io/posts/2020-04-08-not-authorized-to-perform-this-operation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rushichaudhari.github.io/posts/2020-04-08-not-authorized-to-perform-this-operation/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes, when using i3wm I get this error when mounting a partition. But it works for other des like gnome/cinnamon.
Make sure polkit is installed.
Loosen the polkit permissions in your system to allow your normal user to mount devices by creating a file at /etc/polkit-1/localauthority/50-local.d/org.freedesktop.automount.plka (as root!) with the following content:
[Allow Unauthorized mounting/Unmounting] Identity=unix-group:plugdev;cdrom Action=org.freedesktop.udisks2.filesystem-*;org.freedesktop.udisks2.eject* ResultAny=yes ResultInactive=yes ResultActive=yes You can loosen the polkit permissions in your system to allow your normal user to mount devices by creating a file at /etc/polkit-1/localauthority/50-local.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RTL SDR notes</title>
      <link>https://rushichaudhari.github.io/posts/2020-04-09-rtl-sdr-notes-copy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rushichaudhari.github.io/posts/2020-04-09-rtl-sdr-notes-copy/</guid>
      <description>We Need  RTL SDR Dongle RTL SDR Software Computer  SDR works by receiving a analogue radio signal and then using an analog to digital converter to digitalise the signal. The digitalised signal can then be worked in digital processing software. We need GQRX -&amp;gt; osx/ linux git clone https://github.com/csete/gqrx.git cd gqrx mkdir build cd build qmake .. make make install
 sudo apt-get update sudo apt install git cmake libusb-1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Running GUI apps from docker inside WSL2.0 as standalone application</title>
      <link>https://rushichaudhari.github.io/posts/2020-08-19-dockerguiwsl/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rushichaudhari.github.io/posts/2020-08-19-dockerguiwsl/</guid>
      <description>Another day, again my anaconda crashed for no reason. I decided to never use python on windows without linux vm/ docker.
I already had my own docker image created here https://hub.docker.com/repository/docker/rushichaudhari/zipline1.3.0/
but I wondered If I could use GUI in it, luckily I managed to do so.
So here are the steps :-
Pre-requirements:
 Windows 10 WSL  For now, it is necessary to install a third-party App to run the GUI Apps, but Microsoft announced on //build 2020 that they will release soon an improvement that will not require any third-party component to run Linux GUI Apps on Windows Desktop.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting up tigervncserver on arch linux (raspberry-pi)</title>
      <link>https://rushichaudhari.github.io/posts/2020-10-29-setting-up-tigervncserver-on-arch-linux-raspberry-pi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rushichaudhari.github.io/posts/2020-10-29-setting-up-tigervncserver-on-arch-linux-raspberry-pi/</guid>
      <description>Installing tigervnc sudo pacman -Ss tigervnc Editing the environment file ~/.vnc/xstartup functions like .xinitrc and it&amp;rsquo;s sourced by vncserver when being started. At a minimum, users should start a DE from this file. As an example, to start lxde, you&amp;rsquo;ll modify the file to:
$nano ~/.vnc/xstartup #!/bin/bash exec lxde &amp;amp;&amp;gt;/dev/null The file should be executable: $ chmod +x ~/.vnc/xstartup Adding vncserver options $ nano ~/.vnc/config desktop=sandbox geometry=1920x1080 dpi=96 SecurityTypes=none Starting and stopping vncserver via systemd To control vncserver with systemd, first, create systemd unit file for the user</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SSD - things todo to save space on ssd C drive</title>
      <link>https://rushichaudhari.github.io/posts/2020-04-10-ssd-savespace/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rushichaudhari.github.io/posts/2020-04-10-ssd-savespace/</guid>
      <description>Change cache location of Firefox You can do this by creating a new hidden preference.
 Type about:config into the location bar and press enter Accept the warning message that appears, you will be taken to a list of preferences Right-click somewhere in the list and select &amp;ldquo;New &amp;gt; String&amp;rdquo; For the name of the preference type browser.cache.disk.parent_directory For its value type the path to where you want to store the cache Next locate the preference browser.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>To what extent can I get Indian Veg Food in Boston</title>
      <link>https://rushichaudhari.github.io/posts/2020-01-05-a-vegetarians-guide-in-boston/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rushichaudhari.github.io/posts/2020-01-05-a-vegetarians-guide-in-boston/</guid>
      <description>Unfortunately only 3-4% of citizens in the US are vegetarian. After rambling around nearby streets, I got to know veg stuff was obscured everywhere. Even Subway/McDonald&#39;s were no exception. So here is a dynamic N00Bs guide in becoming a Masterchef with vegetarian things available in Boston. Masala Khichidi with Kadhi Pizza toppings on bread P.S. Pizza base coss around 4$ for 2, bread is 1.6$ for a loaf.
Pav Bhaji Pulao Cauliflower Chana(black) h3 { font-family: &#39;Great Vibes&#39;, Helvetica, sans-serif; color: #000; text-shadow: 4px 4px 3px rgba(0,0,0,0.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
