<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>docker on A collection of random ideas so I don&#39;t have to google again</title>
    <link>https://rushichaudhari.github.io/tags/docker/</link>
    <description>Recent content in docker on A collection of random ideas so I don&#39;t have to google again</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 27 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://rushichaudhari.github.io/tags/docker/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Colab Equivalent Pytorch Docker With GPU</title>
      <link>https://rushichaudhari.github.io/posts/2022-03-27-colab-equivalent-pytorch-docker-with-gpu/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rushichaudhari.github.io/posts/2022-03-27-colab-equivalent-pytorch-docker-with-gpu/</guid>
      <description>Dockerfile FROM pytorch/pytorch:1.10.0-cuda11.3-cudnn8-devel WORKDIR /root RUN pip install jupyter jupyterlab EXPOSE 8888 COPY . . CMD jupyter notebook --port=8888 --no-browser --ip=0.0.0.0 --allow-root docker-compose.yml version: &amp;quot;3&amp;quot; services: main: build: . volumes: - .:/root ports: - 8888:8888 network_mode: &amp;quot;host&amp;quot; privileged: true deploy: resources: reservations: devices: - driver: nvidia count: 1 capabilities: [gpu] Run docker-compose build docker-compose run --rm main
Reason?
Colab equivalent Pytorch version 1.10.0 torchtext works torchdata works</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Running the Real Time Voice Cloning in Docker on Arch Linux</title>
      <link>https://rushichaudhari.github.io/posts/2021-12-24-real-time-voice-cloning-docker-arch/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rushichaudhari.github.io/posts/2021-12-24-real-time-voice-cloning-docker-arch/</guid>
      <description>I came across this awesome project called Real Time Voice Cloning by Corentin Jemine and I wanted to give it a shot. I’m currently working on a Arch linux machine with GPU, that could easily run the toolbox, but I wanted an easy way to get everything setup. Docker would do the trick as far as getting it setup, and then through forwarding the X Window System via SSH, I could view and control the program locally as it ran remotely.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alexa AI for reminding important emails and reminders</title>
      <link>https://rushichaudhari.github.io/posts/2021-12-19-alexa-remind-emails/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rushichaudhari.github.io/posts/2021-12-19-alexa-remind-emails/</guid>
      <description>Motivation :- It was the third time I missed reading my email and picking up shifts for my oncampus job. I did try creating labels and filtering them but that didn&amp;rsquo;t show any progress in improvement. It&amp;rsquo;s really stressful when I get the notification that something needs a response from me right away. I had to make sure that I was not missing this next time. It is then when I decided I need to build a system to process and remind me this.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
